milestonesys.com 2019-12-19

# Privacy Policy

Milestone strives to be your reliable partner and your privacy is important to us. We are committed to protecting your personal data and with this Privacy Policy, we will inform you on how we apply your personal data when you visit our website, when you contact us, and when you sign up to join our community.

If you have any questions which are not answered in this Privacy Policy, or you would like to assert your privacy rights to be informed on the data collected, make corrections or deletions, or make withdrawal of consent, you can contact us at.

Milestone Systems A/S  
Group Data Protection  
Banemarksvej 50 C  
2605 Brøndby  
Denmark  
Email: [privacy@milestonesys.com](mailto:privacy@milestonesys.com)

## When you visit our Website

Milestone Systems A/S is responsible for our website and processes data on behalf of the Milestone Group Companies and our local offices. You can find a list of our group companies and local offices at https://www.milestonesys.com/about-us/locations/. This list may be updated from time to time. Milestone works with Partners who market and sell our products, and with Partners who offer Milestone related products, services, and activities. You can find information on our Partner network at https://www.milestonesys.com/community/find-a-milestone-partner/. We are on an ongoing basis expanding our Partner network.

Milestone shares information with the Milestone Group Companies, and with our Partners consistent with this Privacy Policy and applicable laws. We will apply the information to provide and improve our products, services, the content of our website, and our advertising activities. This Privacy Policy outlines the personal data we may collect and store, and how we use personal data for these general business purposes.

**Personal Data**  
Milestone will not collect any personally-identifiable data about you (e.g. your name, address, telephone number, or e-mail address) through our website, unless you have provided it to us voluntarily.

**IP-addresses**  
When you browse on our website you will provide machine readable trails by using your IP-address. Milestone uses cookies to keep statistics on how many users use our sites and how they use them. We may collect information regarding your activities on our website, including your preferences related to our website. This information is aggregated and used to optimize our website and help us to provide useful information to our visitors. This also makes your visit to our website as convenient and interesting as possible. In addition, we use cookies in connection with forms and orders to save the information entered for more seamless experience. Log reports on accesses to our websites and the use of cookies and web analyses are very important for the purpose of improving our sites, increasing their usability and visitors’ satisfaction. Please refer to our Cookie Policy https://www.milestonesys.com/cookie-policy/ for detailed information about how we use cookies and for what purposes.

We will not be able to identify you based on your IP-address alone, but if you provide personal data such as your name, your e-mail, or equal contact information, we will be able to combine your IP-address with your personal data.

When you use our mobile applications

When you use our mobile applications, Milestone does not collect any personally-identifiable data about you. We may collect and use anonymous data to see how mobile users interact with our app and, based on this information, how we can maintain and improve our mobile applications for the users. Before we collect anonymous data, we will ask for your consent for collection and usage of such anonymous data. You may withdraw your consent at any time by changing the application settings. Provided you have given your consent, the anonymous data will be collected automatically: it will be generated either by the use of the application or from the application infrastructure itself. The collected anonymous data include, among other data, the type of mobile device you use, your mobile operating system, the session duration, the version of the application, touch gestures, crash logs, a high level location approximation and other diagnostic data.

## When you participate in our events

When you participate in our events (e.g. MIPS, MPOP, Milestone integration Expo, seminars, conferences, and webinars), you need to be aware that Milestone can photograph and shoot videos, including livestreaming, in public areas during such events, as well as during presentations. Milestone may use images and video in global and public marketing materials, on social media, in educational products and in publications. Your image and voice may be recorded on audio and/or video. You or others may be able to identify you in the photos and/or recordings, and if you identify yourself by name, such personal data may be included in our produced materials. Photos and/or recordings may be edited, copied, exhibited, published or distributed. You will be asked to provide your consent for such photos, audios and videos to be made by Milestone, including livestreaming, when you register for the event on Milestone website. If you are interviewed, or are a speaker at the event, or otherwise actively participate and contribute to the event, we will ask you to provide a specific consent regarding your personal data. If you do not want your personal data to be used by Milestone, you may withdraw your consent or exercise other data subjects’ rights that are granted to you by the data protection laws. Please, see Section “Your Rights” of this Privacy Policy.

## When you provide Personal Data

**Collection and use of Personal Data**  
You may be asked to provide personally-identifiable data to Milestone in order to use our website and the functions we make available for visitors, and for us to respond to your questions or requests. When you create a Milestone log-in or use other of our many services to learn more about our products, make free downloads, or apply our features, we register the personal data you provide in the contact form such as your name, mailing address, phone number, email address, and contact preferences. If you sign up for an event, we may also ask for your meal preferences.

**How we use your Personal Data**  
We use personal data to respond to your requests, or contact you via mail, e-mail, or phone to fulfill your request or provide service communications. We will also use personal data to help us develop and improve our website, services, content, advertising, including through auditing and data analysis, statistics, surveys, research purposes, and other lawful processing for our reasonable business purposes. The personal data we request in our contact forms are minimized to the relevant data required for its purpose, but we may ask for your consent to use your data for other purposes such as marketing activities, see our information below under “Consent”. If you agree to receive our products, Milestone will use your personal data to contact you for marketing similar products.

**Sharing Information**  
From time to time, Milestone will make certain relevant personal data available to our Partners that work together with us to provide products and services, or that help us with marketing to customers. When you ask to be contacted about a Milestone product, a Milestone employee will contact you and/or we may forward your request to our distributor or reseller partners who will contact you and for this purpose, they will receive your personal contact data. You find information on our Partner network at https://www.milestonesys.com/community/find-a-milestone-partner/.

If you chose to participate in competitions or other promotion programs offered by our Partners, we may use the personal data you provide to administer those programs, and we may also provide our Partners with aggregate – but not individual – information about visitors and users of our sites and links to their sites.

Milestone has outsourced certain functions to our service provides and we may share your personal data with our service providers for the specific purpose of their services. These services include information processing, managing and enhancing customer data, providing customer service, assessing your interest in our website and services, and conducting customer research or satisfaction surveys. These service providers are obligated to protect your personal data. See also our information below under “Safeguards for transfer of Personal Data”.

**Consent**  
We may ask for your consent to allow Milestone to contact you, or to keep you posted on Milestone’s latest announcements, or to receive our free newsletter or other marketing activities, online surveys and competitions. You will find consent forms when using Milestone’s website, including when you open a My Milestone account. We will use your email address and other personal data you provide for these marketing activities and for uses as stated in this Privacy Policy.

If you do not want to be on our mailing list for one or more marketing activities, you can opt out anytime by updating your preferences or withdraw you consents by contacting us using [this link](https://pardot.milestonesys.com/preferences?epc_hash=FHmZ_64RVPy5bNsGooMMwzaJbwHXRSUV_Qu1b1rElEo) or by accessing your My Milestone account at https://www.milestonesys.com/my-milestone/.

We will store your personal data while you receive our marketing material and up to six (6) months after you have ceased to be a potential customer for our marketing purposes.

**Terms and Conditions and Policies**  
From time to time, we may use your personal contact data to send important notices, such as communications about changes to our terms, conditions, and policies. Because this information is important to your interaction with Milestone, you may not opt out of receiving these communications as long as you have an ongoing contract with Milestone for delivery of our products or services, or a contract for other long-term purposes.

**Information required for other Legitimate Purpose**  
Milestone may be required by law, legal process, litigation, and/or requests from public and governmental authorities or court order to disclose your personal data. We may also need to disclose personal data if we determine, it is required to enforce our terms and conditions or protect our operations or users. Additionally, in the event of a reorganization, merger, or sale we may transfer any and all personal data we have collected to the relevant third party.

**How we protect your Personal Data  **  
Milestone takes precautions, including administrative, technical, and physical measures, to safeguard your personal data against loss, theft, and misuse, as well as against unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, and destruction. Milestone’s website may use Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) encryption on web pages where personal data is collected. To make purchases from these services, you must use an SSL-enabled browser such as Safari, Firefox or Internet Explorer. Doing so protects the confidentiality of your personal data while it’s transmitted over the Internet.

You may use certain of the services or applications made available by Milestone, like access to post on the Milestone forums, such as Developer Forum or Support Community or our other social networking services. The personal data you share will be visible to other users and can be read, collected, or used by them. Therefore, please notice that when you post personal data in such a forum, the information will be made public.

**Safeguards for transfer of Personal Data**  
Information including personal data may be transferred or accessed by companies and local offices in the Milestone Group Companies or shared with our Partners for purposes as described in this Privacy Policy. Milestone complies with the European Commission’s regulation (EU) 2016/679, General Data Protection Regulation, and any transfer of personal data to Non-EU/EEA countries hosting Milestone companies or offices, Partners or service providers will be subject to safeguards compliant to the EU Commissions Standard Clauses. Learn more about The European Commission’s safeguard clauses on [www.ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection/data-transfers-outside-eu/model-contracts-transfer-personal-data-third-countries_en](https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection/international-dimension-data-protection/standard-contractual-clauses-scc_en).

**Third-Party Sites and Services**  
Milestone’s websites, applications, and services may contain links to our Partners’ websites, products, and services. Milestone’s services may also use or refer to our Partners’ Milestone related products, services or activities. Information collected by our Partners, when you link to their websites, may include location data or contact details, and is governed by their privacy practices. Milestone is not responsible for the content of other companies’ websites or for their practices in collecting personal data. When you visit other websites, you should always read the website’s privacy policy and other relevant policies.

**Retention Policy**  
We will retain your personal data for the period necessary to fulfill the purposes outlined in this Privacy Policy or for such longer retention period as required or permitted by law.

**Your Access to your Personal Data  **  
Milestone makes it easy for you to keep your personal data accurate, complete, and up to date. You can log in to your My Milestone account at https://www.milestonesys.com/login-page/, or when receiving our newsletter, you can use the profile link at the end of our newsletters. If you do not have a My Milestone account, you can contact us at [privacy@milestonesys.com](mailto:privacy@milestonesys.com).

**Your Rights  **  
You have the right to be informed of your personal data which Milestone has stored and processes, and you may at any time require that Milestone ceases the process activities of your personal data. Please contact us by sending an e-mail to [privacy@milestonesys.com](mailto:privacy@milestonesys.com).

If you find that you have reasons to file a complaint against Milestone System for our data processing activities, you may contact the Danish Data Protection Authority; Datatilsynet, Borgergade 28, DK-1300 Copenhagen K, ([www.datatilsynet.dk](http://www.datatilsynet.dk/)).

**Updating our Privacy Policy**  
Milestone may update our Privacy Policy from time to time. We recommend that visitors to our website re-visit this Privacy Policy on occasion to learn of new privacy practices or changes to our Privacy Policy. For any material changes in our Privacy Policy, a notice will be posted on our website along with the updated Privacy Policy.

**Kind regards,**  
 **Milestone Systems A/S**

Last updated: June 4, 2019
